

Mikhail Nasyrov

Senior Software Engineer

mikhail@mnasyrov.com

Novosibirsk, Russia

github.com/mnasyrov

in <u>linkedin.com/mnasyrov</u>



Summary

I lead a frontend team and work on building a video conference service. Going each step from a Software Engineer to a Team Leader helps me **build strong teams**, where every member makes an individual contribution to a common goal.

I have **15+ years** of experience in software development and had a chance to create complex **frontend and backend** services for various applications, working with different technology stacks and paradigms.

I keep constantly learning new, and I'm open to new ideas. I develop two **open source projects** for frontend apps: <u>Ditox.js</u> - a dependency injection container, and RxEffects - a reactive state and effect management.

$\downarrow \uparrow \downarrow$ Qualification

General

- · Software development, architecture, analytics
- · Team leading and mentoring
- Master of Science in Information Technology

Frontend

- Javascript, Typescript, Flow.js
- · React, Redux, Electron, RxJS, Angular, Cordova, Ionic
- WebRTC, WebSocket, gRPC, JSON-RPC
- REST API, HTML, CSS

Backend

- Java, Kotlin, Javascript, Python, C#
- Spring, Hibernate, Rxlava, Node, is
- Docker, Nginx, HAProxy



(10 mos)

Experience

Sberbank of Russia PJC O

Mar 2021 – Present

Frontend Team Lead | <u>Jazz</u> – a video conference service

I work for the SberDevices department and lead a frontend team, which develops a video conference service.

My responsibilities:

- Developing web and desktop applications.
- Developing an SDK to integrate the video service to the third-party web applications.
- · Reviewing analytics and requirements for new features.
- Managing a technical stack and backlog for the web project.
- Planning sprints according to a roadmap of product owners.
- Defining processes for the frontend team.
- · Making code reviewing and mentoring the team.

After handing the project over to me, the following had done in 3 months:

- · Reviewed the state of the project and made a technical roadmap.
- Grew the team to 6 people since only one developer remained from the previous team.
- Stabilized video calls and delivered applications to public beta access.

Technologies: Javascript, Typescript, React, RxJS, WebRTC, Electron, Node.js, IndexedDB, Dexie.js, Ditox.js, RxEffects, Effector.js, Jest, Playwright, Webpack, HTML, CSS, Python, Docker

Dialog LLC

Mar 2019 - Mar 2021 (2 yr)

\mathbf{O}

Lead Software Engineer | Dialog – an enterprise messenger platform

I worked on a web platform for an enterprise messenger, including developing core and SDK components, web and desktop applications. I designed some of the main parts of architecture and created low-level pieces of the platform like a database layer and gRPC API clients.

Alongside frontend development, I supported a backend service for proxying gRPC API calls from web applications to microservices.

I mentored teammates, performed code reviewing and conducted technical interviews.

Technologies: Javascript, Typescript, Flow.js, React, RxJS, Jest, Electron, Node.js, Java, HTML, CSS, Webpack, Dexie.js

Monento

Jan 2016 - Mar 2019 (3 yr 3 mos)

Founder, Lead Software Engineer | Monento – a personal finance app

Launched own project Monento - a personal finance manager. It is a cross-platform application on a frontend side and microservices on a backend side. I published it in Apple AppStore, Google Play and Snapcraft. The following developed:

- Cross-platform application for Android, iOS, macOS, Windows and Linux.
- Replication service for syncing mobile clients. It uses CRDT operations and end-to-end encryption.
- Billing service integrated with the Keycloak authentication server and the application stores such as Apple AppStore and Google Play.

Technologies: Typescript, Javascript, Angular, Cordova, Ionic, Electron, Node.js, Java, Kotlin, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Webpack, Docker.

Xored Software, Inc.

Oct 2011 – Dec 2015 (4 vr 3 mos)

Team Lead | Outsourced software development

My responsibilities were software development, system analytics, project planning, architecture design of applications and systems, researching and prototyping. I led a team of 7 engineers and handled communication with customer teams. Mentored teammates and did code reviewing.

Projects:

- <u>Spirent Velocity</u> a platform for labs that unifies device test and network topology automation.
- <u>Cisco Prime Infrastructure</u> a solution that simplifies the management of wireless and wired networks, monitoring end-user connectivity and application performance.
- LogAnalyzer a plugin for the Jenkins CI server that analyses big build logs by a custom PEG-parser and provides structured output.

Technologies:

- JavaScript, React, AngularJS, Dojo, Fantom language, HTML, CSS
- Java, JavaEE, Spring, Hibernate, Tapestry, Arquillian, Wildfly, Tomcat, JUnit, Maven
- Python, Django, C++, PostgreSQL, Jenkins

Novoprof B.V.

Jan 2008 – Aug 2011 (3 yr 8 mos)

Software Engineer | Outsourced software development

Web and desktop app development. Analysis of tasks and product requirements, estimating and prototyping solutions. Participation in designing app architectures. Performance optimization of apps and databases. I had the experience of working with distributed European teams on wide range of projects: from a <u>financial accounting service</u>, to a monitoring and reporting system for sea vessels that allowed to <u>reduce CO2 emission</u> by 17% by operated vessels.

Technologies: C#, VB.NET, ASP.NET, WPF, WinForms, MS SQL, JavaScript, AJAX, JQuery, NUnit, NAnt, MSBuild.

ARL Consulting B.V.

Jul 2007 – Dec 2007 (6 mos)

Software Engineer | e-Yield – a booking service for cargo delivery

My responsibilities were web application development, task analysis, estimations, implementation and testing.

I worked on the eYield project – booking service for cargo delivery. I assisted a project manager and business analysts to elaborate features and make task estimations. I developed parts of the web application in C# and .NET framework. Occasionally, I took part in a manual testing session to help QA deliver releases.

Technologies: C#, ASP.NET, MS SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, web services.

Softomate

Jul 2005 – Sep 2005 (3 mos)

Software Engineer

I worked on the development of extensions for the Mozilla Firefox browser.

Technologies: JavaScript, XUL platform, HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL.

Education

Master of Science in Information Technology and Computer Engineering

Novosibirsk State Technical University, 2001 - 2007

- Computer analysis and data interpretation
- · Computers, computer systems, and networks

Languages

- English B2 Upper-intermediate
- Russian Native



Contests

• ACM-ICPC 2002/2003 NEERC (semifinal)